Guide to the Consolidation Coal Company Records, 1854-1971 AIS.2011.03
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Predecessor & Subsidiary Companies' Minute Books, III.
  - Consolidation Coal Company (West Virginia), 48.
    Incorporated: November 20, 1945, in W.V; Demised: dissolved February 8, 1950; Predecessor: None; Successor: Pittsburgh Consolidation Coal Company; Statistics: Operating company for former West Virginia Division mines from December 1, 1945 through December 15, 1949.
    - Minutes of Stockholders and Board of Directors Meetings, November 20, 1945-February 8, 1950 (Box 6)
  - Consolidation Coal Products Company, 49.
    Incorporated: October 20, 1922, in DE; Demised: Unknown; Predecessor: None; Successor: None; Statistics: Manufactured an artificial fuel called "Carbocoal".
    - Minutes of Stockholders and Board of Directors Meetings, October 20, 1922-January 26, 1928 (Box 14)
  - Consolidation Coastwise Company, 50.
    Incorporated: December 11, 1914, in Mass; Demised: February 4, 1932; Predecessor: None; Successor: Metropolitan Marine and Fuel Company; Statistics: Operated coastwise fleet for shipment of coal to New England. Assets sold to Metropolitan Marine and Fuel Company.
    - Minutes of Stockholders and Board of Directors Meetings, December 11, 1914-February 4, 1932 (Box 14)
  - Courtney Fire Brick Company, 51.
    Incorporated: April 21, 1903, in PA; Demised: December 15, 1944; Predecessor: None; Successor: Pittsburgh Coal Company; Statistics: Manufacturer of fire brick at Monongahela, Pa.
    - Minutes of Stockholders Meetings, April 21, 1903-April 25, 1933 (Box 14)
    - Minutes of Board of Directors Meetings, August 4, 1903-December 29, 1911
    - Minutes of Board of Directors Meetings, January 25, 1912-June 15, 1931
    - Minutes of Board of Directors Meetings, September 10, 1931-August 10, 1933
    - Minutes of Stockholders and Board of Directors Meetings, April 25, 1934-December 15, 1944
    - Memoranda Book, April 25, 1938-November 7, 1944
  - Cumberland and Pennsylvania Railroad Company, 52.
    Incorporated: May 4, 1850, in MD; Demised: Sold by Consolidation Coal Company, May 1944; Predecessor: Mount Savage Iron Company; Successor: Western Maryland Railway Company; Statistics: Operated railroad in Cumberland, Md. Coal Field. Subsidiary of Consolidation Coal Company, 1864-1944. Sold to Western Maryland Railway Company, May 1944.
    - Minutes, October 16, 1924-May 12, 1944 (Box 14)
  - Disco Company, 53.
    Incorporated: May 23, 1946, in PA; Demised: March 16, 1951; Predecessor: Pittsburgh Coal Carbonization Company; Successor: None; Statistics: Manufactured smokeless fuel briquettes and extracted coal tar from coal at Imperial, Pa.
    - Minutes of Stockholders and Board of Directors Meetings, May 23, 1946-March 16, 1951 (Box 15)
  - Dunlap Coal Company, 54.
    Incorporated: June 4, 1915, in W.V; Demised: December 2, 1918; Predecessor: None; Successor: Consolidation Coal Company; Statistics: Operated mines in Pike County, Ky.
    - Minutes of Stockholders and Board of Directors Meetings, June 4, 1915-December 2, 1918 (Box 15)
  - Elkins Gas Coal Company, 55.
    Incorporated: March 7, 1892, in PA; Demised: April 20, 1914; Predecessor: None; Successor: Pittsburgh Coal Company; Statistics: Operated mines in Westmoreland County, Pa. Land sold to Pittsburgh Coal Company in July 1911.
    - Minutes of Stockholders and Board of Directors, March 28, 1892-May 15, 1913 (Box 15)
  - Fairmont and Somerset Equipment Company, 56.
    Incorporated: March 9, 1906, in DE; Demised: August 20, 1908; Predecessor: None; Successor: None; Statistics: Owned and operated railroad coal cars for Fairmont Coal Company and Somerset Coal Company. All assets sold to Baltimore & Ohio Railroad Company in 1907.
    - Minutes of Stockholders and Board of Directors Meetings, March 15, 1906-August 20, 1908 (Box 15)
  - Fairmont Coal Company, 57.
    Incorporated: June 20, 1901, in W.V; Demised: dissolved December 31, 1936; Predecessors: Montana Coal & Coke Company, West Fairmont Coal & Coke Company, Briar Hill Coal & Coke Company, Gaston Gas Coal Company, Highland Coal & Coke Company, the Monongah Company, Palatine Coal Company, Pennois Coal & Coke Company, Worthington Coal & Coke Company, West Fork Mining Company, Middleton Coal Company, American Coal & Coke Company, Hutchinson-Ehlen Coal Company, Mason Coal & Coke Company, Hutchinson Coal Company, Meadowbrook Coal & Coke Company, Riverdale Mining Company; Successor: Consolidation Coal Company Statistics: Formed by Johnson M. Camden interests. Operated mines in northern West Virginia. Acquired by Consolidation Coal Company in 1903. All property transferred to Consolidation Coal Company in November 1935.
    - Minutes of Stockholders and Board of Directors Meetings--Minute Book No.1, June 22, 1901-June 27, 1901 (Box 15)
    - Minutes of Stockholders and Board of Directors Meetings--Minute Book No.2, August 1, 1901–January 26, 1904
    - Minutes of Stockholders and Board of Directors Meetings--Minute Book No.3 (Volume 27), March 16, 1904–July 15, 1907 (Oversize 101)
    - Minutes of Stockholders and Board of Directors Meetings--Minute Book No.4 (Volume 28), October 4, 1907–March 21, 1917 (Oversize 102)
    - Minutes of Stockholders and Board of Directors Meetings--Minute Book No.5 (Volume 29), March 21, 1917-March 16, 1921
    - Minutes of Stockholders and Board of Directors Meetings--Minute Book No.6 (Volume 30), March, 16, 1921-March 17, 1926 (Oversize 103)
    - Minutes of Stockholders and Board of Directors Meetings--Minute Book No.7 (Volume 31), May 5, 1926-December 1, 1936
    - Minutes of Stockholders and Board of Directors Meetings--Minute Book No.2, August 2, 1901–July 2, 1906 (Box 15)
    - Minutes of Stockholders and Board of Directors Meetings--Minute Book No.3, July 2, 1906–July 17, 1909 (Box 16)
    - Minutes of Stockholders and Board of Directors, December 2, 1926–December 1, 1936
  - Fairmont Coal Mining Company, 58.
    Incorporated: September 12, 1900, in W.V; Demised: April 5, 1904 (Date of last meeting.); Predecessor: None; Successor: Fairmont Coal Company; Statistics: Sales company for coal operators of Fairmont District. All assets and leases sold to Fairmont Coal Company, June 30, 1901.
    - Minutes of Stockholders and Board of Directors Meetings, October 6, 1900 - April 5, 1904 (Box 16)
  - Fairmont Coals, Inc., 59.
    Incorporated: March 14, 1938, in W.V; Demised: dissolved January 30, 1948; Predecessor: None; Successor: None Statistics: Sales company for coal operators in Northern West Virginia, District No. 3, under the Guffey Act. Jointly owned by Consolidation Coal Company, Koppers Coal Division of Eastern Gas & Fuel Associates, Jamison Coal & Coke Company, et al.
    - Minutes of Stockholder and Board of Directors Meetings, March 14, 1938-January 30, 1948 (Box 16)
  - Fairmont Lake Shippers Association, 60.
    Incorporated: March 16, 1900, in W.V; Demised: Unknown; Predecessor: None; Successor: None; Statistics: Organized by representatives of the Montana Coal & Coke Company, the Monongah Coal & Coke Company, the J.A. Clark Coal Company, the Worthington Coal & Coke Company and the Highland Coal & Coke Company to handle sales and shipments at Lake ports.
    - Minutes of Stockholders & Board of Directors Meetings, March 16, 1900-June 5, 1901 (Box 16)
  - Fairmont Mining Machinery Company, 61.
    Incorporated: January 2, 1906, in W.V; Demised: May 1, 1935; Predecessor: None; Successor: Fairmont Machinery Company; Statistics: Manufactures coal-mining machinery. Subsidiary of Fairmont Coal Company and then of Consolidation Coal Company.
    - Minutes of Stockholders and Board of Directors Meetings--Minute Book No.1, January 2, 1906-February 23, 1915 (Box 16)
    - Minutes of Stockholders and Board of Directors Meetings--Minute Books No. 2, February 8, 1916-February 8, 1921
    - Minutes of Stockholders and Board of Directors Meetings--Minute Books No. 3, February 8, 1921-October 31, 1923
    - Minutes of Stockholders and Board of Directors Meetings--Minute Books No. 4, February 23, 1923-May 1, 1935
  - Fairmont Supply Company, 62.
    Incorporated: January 12, 1921, in W.V; Demised: June 18, 1951, by merger; Predecessor: None; Successor: Fairmont Machinery Company; Statistics: Dealer in mine and mill supplies for Consolidation Coal Company.
    - Minutes of Stockholders and Board of Directors Meetings--Minute Book No.1, January 12, 1921 - July 24, 1933 (Box 17)
    - Minutes of Stockholders and Board of Directors Meetings--Minute Book No. 2, February 13, 1934-December 29, 1948
    - Minutes of Stockholders and Board of Directors Meetings--Minute Book No. 3, January 17, 1949-June 18, 1951
  - First National Company, 63.
    Incorporated: January 5, 1917, in W.V; Demised: October 30, 1917; Predecessor: None; Successor: Utilities Corporation; Statistics: Owned Citizens Dollar Savings Bank Building and Home Savings Bank Building at Fairmont, W.Va.. Name changed to Utilities Corporation on October 30, 1917.
    - Minutes of Stockholders and Board of Directors Meetings, January 5, 1917-October 20, 1917 (Box 17)
  - First Pool Monongahela Gas Coal Company, 64.
    Incorporated: April 25, 1887, in PA; Demised: July 25, 1911; Predecessor: None; Successor: Pittsburgh Coal Company of Pennsylvania; Statistics: Operated coal mines on Monongahela River in Allegheny County, Pa..; property sold to Pittsburgh Coal Company of Pennsylvania in 1904.
    - Minutes of Stockholders and Board of Directors Meetings, April 25, 1887-December 1, 1911 (Box 17)
  - Flemington and Astor Railway Company, 65.
    Incorporated: December 13, 1900, in W.V; Demised: June 28, 1920 (Date of last meeting. Dissolution discussed and approved.); Predecessor: None; Successor: None; Statistics: Charter for unbuilt railroad. Controlled by Consolidation Coal Company.
    - Minutes of Stockholders and Board of Directors Meetings, December 14, 1900-June 28, 1920 (Box 17)
  - Fort Pitt & Leasdale Railroad Company, 66.
    Incorporated: April 2, 1900, in PA; Demised: September 22, 1909; Predecessor: None; Successor: None; Statistics: Charter for unbuilt railroad. Controlled by Pittsburgh Coal Company.
    - Minutes of Stockholders and Board of Directors Meetings, April 2, 1900-September 22, 1909 (Box 17)
  - Glen Falls Coal and Coke Company, 67.
    Incorporated: in W.Va., date unknown; Demised: 1901; Predecessor: None; Successor: Brier Hill Coal and Coke Company; Statistics: Operated mines in Fairmont District. Assets sold to Brier Hill Coal and Coke Company in January 1901.
    - Minutes (In Watson Supply Company volume), January 12, 1901-January 14, 1901 (Box 33)
  - Great Lakes Coal Mining Company, 68.
    Incorporated: March 22, 1917, in Ohio; Demised: December 22, 1923, by merger; Predecessor: Roby Coal Company; Successor: New Pittsburgh Coal Company (Ohio); Statistics: Operated mines in southern Ohio. Acquired by Pittsburgh Coal Company in 1923.
    - Minutes of Stockholders and Board of Directors Meetings, March 22, 1917-December 22, 1923 (Box 17)
  - Greendale Coal Mining Company, 69.
    Incorporated: April 19, 1898, in Maine; Demised: dissolved May 28, 1903; Predecessor: None; Successor: New Pittsburgh Coal Company (Ohio); Statistics: Operated mines in Athens County, Ohio. Leases sold to New Pittsburgh Coal Company in 1902.
    - Minutes of Stockholders and Board of Directors Meetings, March 25, 1898-May 28, 1903 (Box 17)
  - Greer and Van Eman Railroad Company, 70.
    Incorporated: November 15, 1899, in Pa; Demised: stricken from record June 1909; Predecessor: None; Successor: None; Statistics: Charter for unbuilt railroad. Controlled by Pittsburgh Coal Company.
    - Minutes of Stockholders & Board of Directors Meetings, January 13, 1903-September 22, 1909 (Box 17)
  - Hanna Coal Company, 1931-1946; 71.
    Incorporated: June 15, 1900, in Ohio; Demised: Unknown; Predecessors: Wheeling and Lake Erie Coal Mining Company; Bituminous Investment Company; Successor: Hanna Coal Company (1946-1950); Statistics: Incorporated as Wheeling and Lake Erie Coal Mining Company. Acquired mining properties of Bituminous Investment Company and renamed Hanna Coal Company, December 14, 1931; subsidiary of Hanna Coal Company (Del.), which was renamed Hanna Coal Sales Company (Del.) in 1939.
    - Minutes, December 14, 1931-December 11, 1939 (Box 18)
  - Hanna Coal Company, 1946-1950; 72.
    Incorporated: June 6, 1946, in Ohio; Demised: dissolved June 26, 1950; Predecessor: Hanna Coal Company (1931-1946); Successor: Pittsburgh Consolidation Coal Company; Statistics: Acquired the coal properties of the old Hanna Coal Company, a subsidiary of M.A. Hanna Company. The old Hanna Coal Company was then renamed Hanna Lands Company.
    - Minutes of Stockholders and Board of Directors Meetings, June 6, 1946-June 26, 1950 (Box 18)
  - Hannastown Supply Company, 73.
    Incorporated: September 9, 1930, in Pa; Demised: April 19, 1955; Predecessor: Hempfield Supply Company; Successor: Jamison Coal & Coke Company; Statistics: Acquired property of Hempfield Supply Company. Operated company stores associated with Jamison Coal & Coke Company in Westmoreland County, Pa. and in W.Va.
    - Minutes of Stockholders and Board of Directors Meetings, August 27, 1930-April 19, 1955 (Box 18)
  - Harmar Coal Company, 74.
    Incorporated: In Pa., date unknown; Demised: June 15, 1927; Predecessor: None; Successor: Bessemer Coal and Coke Corporation; Statistics: Incorporated under the laws of the Commonwealth of Pennsylvania. Purchased by Bessemer Coal and Coke Corporation on June 15, 1927.
    - Minutes of Stockholders and Directors Meetings (in Minute Book No. 2 of Indianola Coal Company), January 13, 1919-June 15, 1927 (Box 18)
  - Highland Coal and Coke Company, 75.
    Incorporated: May 25, 1898, in W.V; Demised: April 5, 1904; Predecessor: None; Successor: Fairmont Coal Company; Statistics: Operated mines in northern W.Va. Sold to Fairmont Coal Company in 1901.
    - Minutes of Stockholders and Board of Directors Meetings--Minute Book No.1, May 25, 1898-April 9, 1901 (Box 18)
    - Minutes of Stockholders and Board of Directors Meetings--Minute Book No.2, April 22, 1901-April 5, 1904
  - Houston Coal & Oil Company, Inc., 76.
    Incorporated: October 27, 1932, in N.J.; Demised: dissolved December 30, 1936; Predecessor: None; Successor: None; Statistics: Operated coal and oil terminal at Port Newark, N.J. Acquired by Consolidation Coal Company in March 1936.
    - Minutes of Stockholders and Board of Directors Meetings, October 29, 1932-October 30, 1936 (Box 18)
  - Houstonville Coal Railroad Company, 77.
    Incorporated: November 28, 1899, in Pa.; Demised: stricken from record June 1909; Predecessor: None; Successor: None; Statistics: Charter for unbuilt railroad. Controlled by Pittsburgh Coal Company.
    - Minutes of Stockholders and Board of Directors Meetings, January 13, 1903-September 22, 1909 (Box 18)
  - Huntington & St. Louis Towboat Company, 78.
    Incorporated: November 1881; Demised: dissolved December 26, 1917; Successor: Pittsburgh Coal Company Statistics: Operated coal boats on Ohio and Mississippi Rivers. Acquired by Monongahela River Consolidated Coal & Coke Company.
    - Volume 32, November 16, 1881-December 28, 1916 (Oversize 103)
  - Hutton-Beale Coal Company, 79.
    Incorporated: January 4, 1923, in W.Va; Demised: Unknown; Predecessor: None; Successor: None; Statistics: Planned to operate mines in Fairmont District. No indication of any activity after organization.
    - Minutes of Stockholders and Board of Directors Meetings, January 4, 1923-January 16, 1923 (Box 18)
  - Illinois Collieries Company, 80.
    Incorporated: October 30, 1903, in Ill.; Demised: Bankrupt ca. 1916; Predecessors: Jones & Adams Company, Chicago Virden Coal Company, Virden Coal Company, Girard Coal Company, Litchfield Mining & Power Company, Sorento Coal Company; Successor: Montour Coal Company (Ill.); Statistics: Incorporated under the laws of the State of Illinois as the United Collieries Company. Renamed Illinois Collieries Company in March 1904. Operated mines in southern Illinois. Debtor of Pittsburgh Coal Company.
    - Minutes of Stockholders and Board of Directors Meetings, September 30, 1903-June 17, 1916 (Box 18)
  - Indianola Coal Company, 81.
    Incorporated: August 4, 1903, in Pa.; Demised: June 15, 1927; Predecessor: None; Successor: Bessemer Coal and Coke Corporation; Statistics: Owned coal land in Allegheny County; property sold to Inland Collieries Company in 1917.
    - Minutes of Stockholders and Board of Directors Meetings (Volume 33), August 4, 1903-April 8, 1919 (Oversize 103)
    - Minutes of Stockholders and Board of Directors Meetings, September 29, 1919-June 15, 1927 (Box 18)
  - Industrial Supply Company, 82.
    Incorporated: May 26, 1924, in W.Va.; Demised: Unknown; Predecessor: None; Successor: None; Statistics: Planned to operate a mine supplies and building supplies business at Fairmont. No indication of any activity after organization.
    - Minutes of Stockholders and Board of Directors Meetings, May 24, 1924-May 30, 1924 (Box 18)
  - Jefferson Coal Company, 83.
    Incorporated: 1901, in Ohio; Demised: September 24, 1952; Predecessor: None; Successor: Pittsburgh Consolidation Coal Company; Statistics: Jointly owned by New York Central Railroad (52%) and M.A. Hanna Company (48%). Operated mines in Jefferson County, Ohio. Pittsburgh Consolidation Coal Company acquired Hanna interest in 1949 and New York Central interest in 1952.
    - Minutes of Stockholders and Board of Directors Meetings-Minute Book No.1, June 19, 1901-November 21, 1923 (Box 18)
    - Minutes of Stockholders and Board of Directors Meetings-Minute Book No.2, January 2, 1924-October 9, 1931 (Box 19)
    - Minutes of Stockholders and Board of Directors Meetings (2 vols.), January 19, 1942-July 31, 1952
  - Jenkins Realty Company, 84.
    Incorporated: October 8, 1940, in W.Va.; Demised: January 28, 1941; Predecessor: None; Successor: Consolidation Coal Company; Statistics: Operated coal mines and owned coal and timber lands in Letcher County, Ky.; subsidiary of Consolidation Coal Company.
    - Minutes of Stockholders and Board of Directors Meetings, October 8, 1940-December 31, 1943 (Box 19)
  - John F. Irvine Coal Company, Ltd., 85.
    Incorporated: August 15, 1904, in La.; Demised: dissolved January 5, 1918; Predecessor: John F. Irvine & Son; Successor: None; Statistics: Operated coal shipping business at Bayou Sara, La.
    - Minutes, August 15, 1904-January 5, 1918 (Box 19)
  - Jones & Adams Company, 86.
    Incorporated: December 27, 1898, in Ill.; Demised: Passed out of Pittsburgh Coal Company family in May 1912; Predecessor: Adams Coal Company; Successor: Pittsburgh Coal Company of Wisconsin; Statistics: Incorporated under the laws of the State of Illinois as the Adams Coal Company. The name was formally changed to the Jones & Adams Company on February 14, 1900. Operated coal docks on Great Lakes. Also operated mines in southern Illinois, which were sold to the Illinois Collieries Company in 1904. Operations assumed by Pittsburgh Coal Company of Wisconsin on Aug. 1, 1906; stock sold by Pittsburgh Coal Company of Wisconsin to Island Creek Coal Dock Company, May 1912.
    - Minutes of Stockholders and Board of Directors Meetings, December 27, 1898-November 26, 1912 (Box 19)
  - Jos. Walton & Company, Inc., 87.
    Incorporated: May 1894 in Ky.; Demised: renamed June 10, 1913; Predecessor: Jos. Walton & Co.; Successor: Pittsburgh Coal Company (Kentucky); Statistics: Operated coal yards at Louisville. Acquired by Monongahela River Consolidated Coal & Coke Company in October 1899. Renamed Pittsburgh Coal Company (Kentucky), January 8, 1943.
    - Minutes of Stockholders and Board of Directors Meetings, May 28, 1894–June 10, 1913 (Box 19)
  - Kelley Coal Company, 88.
    Incorporated: May 9, 1910, in W.Va.; Demised: dissolved January 11, 1913; Predecessor: None; Successor: Consolidation Coal Company; Statistics: Operated coal mines in Boyd, Pike and Letcher Counties, Ky.; sold to Consolidation Coal Company in November 1914.
    - Minutes of Stockholders and Board of Directors Meetings, May 9, 1910-January 11, 1913 (Box 19)
  - Lee and Hamilton Coal Company, 89.
    Incorporated: January 10, 1905, in Pa.; Demised: November 7, 1912; Predecessor: Lee & Hamilton, Incorporated; Successor: Saw Mill Run Coal and Supply Company; Statistics: Incorporated as Lee & Hamilton, Incorporated; renamed Lee and Hamilton Coal Company, March 29, 1905; operated coal yards in Allegheny County; jointly owned by Pittsburgh Coal Company and Monongahela River Consolidated Coal & Coke Company; property sold to Saw Mill Run Coal and Supply Company, October 14, 1912.
    - Minute Books, January 4, 1905-November 7, 1912 (Box 19)
    - Minute Books, January 8, 1908-January 9, 1911
  - Lehigh Coal and Coke Company, 90.
    Incorporated: April 29, 1896, in Wisc.; Demised: No date provided; Predecessor: None; Successor: None; Statistics: Operated coal terminals at Superior, Wisc
    - Minutes, April 29, 1896-May 17, 1901 (Box 19)
  - Letcher-Elkhorn Land Company, 91.
    Incorporated: January 10, 1923, in Ky.; Demised: dissolved March 15, 1950; Predecessor: None; Successor: Pittsburgh Consolidation Coal Company; Statistics: Owned coal lands in Letcher County, Ky. Assets sold to Pittsburgh Consolidation Coal Company in 1948.
    - Minutes of Stockholders and Board of Directors Meetings, January 19, 1923-March 15, 1950 (Box 20)
  - M.H. Hussey & Company, 92.
    Incorporated: December 1, 1930, in Ill.; Demised: dissolved March 1, 1948; Predecessor: M.H. Hussey & Co. (partnership); Successor: North Western-Hanna Fuel Company; Statistics: Incorporated as M.H. Hussey Coal Company. Renamed M.H. Hussey & Company, December 23, 1931. Operated coal, lumber and feed business at Lake Forest, Ill. Sold to North Western-Hanna Fuel Company in 1943.
    - Minutes, December 8, 1930-March 1, 1948 (Box 20)
  - Manown Manufacturing Company, 93.
    Incorporated: December 4, 1895, in Pa.; Demised: dissolved January 4, 1943; Predecessor: None; Successor: Pittsburgh Coal Company; Statistics: Acquired by Pittsburgh Coal Company in 1899.
    - Minutes, January 2, 1906-November 16, 1942 (Box 20)
  - Mansfield Coal & Coke Company, 94.
    Incorporated: March 14, 1864, in Pa.; Demised: dissolved April 20, 1914; Predecessor: Mansfield Coal and Lime Company; Successor: Pittsburgh Coal Company of Pennsylvania; Statistics: Incorporated as the Mansfield Coal and Lime Company. Renamed Mansfield Coal & Coke Company in June 1872. Assets sold to Pittsburgh Coal Company in March 1904.
    - Minutes, March 14, 1864-May 10, 1884 (Box 20)
    - Minutes, July 29, 1884-March 24, 1904
    - Minutes, March 24, 1904-February 10, 1914
  - Maryland Construction and Contracting Company, 95.
    Incorporated: 1903 in Md.; Demised: dissolved December 1927; Successor: Consolidation Coal Company; Statistics: Built a system of mine drainage tunnels in the Cumberland Coal Fields, Allegany County, Md.
    - Corporate Records, September 23, 1903-December 9, 1927 (Box 20)
  - Massillon Coal Mining Company, 96.
    Incorporated: May 28, 1901, in Ohio; Demised: dissolved September 18, 1930; Predecessors: Central Coal Company, Sonnhalter Coal Company, James Mullins Coal Company, Howells Mining Company, Howells Coal Company, Fox Lake Coal Company, Warwick Coal Company, Fox Mining Company, Massillon Mining Company, et al.; Successor: Wheeling and Lake Erie Coal Mining Company; Statistics: Incorporated by D. R. Hanna interests for the purpose of consolidating smaller mining companies in Massillon Coal Field of northeastern Ohio. Sold all property and assets to the Wheeling and Lake Erie Coal Mining Company in 1930.
    - Minutes of Stockholders and Board of Directors Meetings- Minute Book No.1, May 28, 1901-January 7, 1907 (Box 20)